Guide to the Victoria Schuck papers, Circa 1974-1980 MVC0012.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Victoria Schuck papers
1974-1980
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Schuck, Victoria
MVC0012.RG
2 Linear Feet
Materials from the Presidency of Victoria Schuck from 1974-1980. The contents includes personal and professional correspondence, photographs, inauguration materials and awards.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, official inaugural materils, posters, photos, and news paper clippings. The material dates from 1974-1980 and pertains to the presidency of Victoria Schuck at Mount Vernon College.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Correspondence, Inauguration, and Press, awards, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Victoria Schuck was president of Mount Vernon College from 1978 to 1980. Ms. Schuck received her PhD in 1937 from Stanford University and was a well known political scientist who focused on advancing the role of women in her field. Prior to her appointment as President she was a professor of political science at Mount Holyoke College.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired by GWU upon merger with Mount Vernon College. Collection transferred to Foggy Bottom campus in 2009.
Women -- Education; Political science; Mount Vernon College
- Correspondence, 1974-1980; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  The contents of this series includes letters, cards, and telegrams that range in date from 1974-1980. The material represents both personal and professional correspondence leading up to and during Victoria Schuck's time in office.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Barnard College Letters, 1974; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Book Collection, 1980; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Congratulatory Messages, 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Harvard University's Acceptance of Inaugural Invitation, 1978; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1977-1978; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence, 1978; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Personal Letters and Cards, 1977; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Personal Letters and Cards, 1977; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Inauguration, 1977-1978; Series 2
  This series includes written speeches, notes, official programs, and invitations from the inauguration of Victoria Schuck. The material dates from 1977-1978.
  - Inaugural Speech, 1978 April 13; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Invitation List, 1977; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invitations, 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program, 1978 April 13; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Press, awards, and photographs, 1977-1980; Series 3
  This series contains photographs, newspaper clippings, certificates, and press clippings pertaining to Victoria Schuck and her appointment as President of Mount Vernon College. The material dates from 1977-1980.
  - American University Certificate, 1978; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commencement Photos, 1977; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Inauguration Photos, 1978 April 13; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Library Posters, undated; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1979; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Press, 1977-1980; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Washington College Certificate, 1978; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 7)